Christine Trant Front End Developer

London

07518514881

in linkedin.com/in/christinetrant/

k christinetrant.com

github.com/christinetrant

PROFILE

Open to a new opportunity for a new professional challenge where I can continue to upskill and stay up to date with the latest technologies.

I am an experienced and motivated developer with over 2 years of experience in developing and maintaining websites. I am skilled in WordPress, JavaScript, React, Node.js & PHP, with a solid understanding of SQL databases and headless CMS.

I have the ability to work effectively in both a team and individual settings, with a track record of meeting project deadlines and exceeding customer expectations.

SKILLS

HTML | CSS | Javascript | Content Management Systems & creating custom themes (WordPress)

React and Node.js | Gatsby | Sanity Headless CMS | API Integration | PHP

Version Control (Git & Command Line)

EDUCATION

Ballyfermot College of Further Education

2010 - 2012 | Dublin, Ireland

Digital Media

Higher National Diploma

University College Dublin

2004 - 2008 | Dublin, Ireland

Computer Science

BSc. (Hons.) Grade 2:1

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Umi Digital03-2020 – presentDeveloperLondon, United Kingdom

I was initially hired as a junior developer

- Maintain existing client sites, fix bugs & add new features
- Create bespoke WordPress sites for new clients in collaboration with the design team and account managers
- Most recent project was to create a bespoke client site using Gatsby.js with Sanity as the headless CMS

Morgan Spencer Recruitment

06-2019 – present | London

Temporary Agency Administrator

General administration duties: reception, travel booking (flights, trains), facilities

Local Pensions Partnership

02-2017 - 04-2019 | London

Senior Facilities Support Officer

I initially began as a temp & was offered a full-time position

- Created & rolled out online risk assessments company-wide on the e-learning portal
- Helping the ISO accreditation team as an Internal Auditor:
 - Logging any incidents that were an ISO risk
 - Updating the ISO Risk register in preparation for upcoming audits
- Updating company intranet page with relevant facilities information & updates

• Working within the Facilities team to keep the office running smoothly & gain valuable office experience in London

Morgan Spencer Recruitment

2016 – 2017 | London

Temorary Agency Adminstrator

General administration duties: reception, dictation, filing, data entry

★ DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Personal Portfolio: christinetrant.com ℰ for more projects

Body Works West ∅ London

A bespoke Wordpress theme using ACFs, SCSS & Gulp created from a Figma design for a health club in London

Bromley Court Hotel \mathscr{D}

A bespoke Wordpress theme using ACFs, SCSS & Gulp created from a Figma design for a hotel in London

The Resident Hotels

A bespoke Wordpress theme using ACFs, SCSS & Gulp created from a Figma design for a collection of hotels in the UK

Concentration - Matching Card Game

Developed a matching game using vanilla JavaScript with the following features:

- Time elapsed until you complete the game (all cards revealed)
- Total Moves count before you complete the game
- Reset button to start the game over

Utilised: JavaScript (ES6), HTML, CSS

RoboFriends

React based project

- integrated third party API to get user details
- search function

Utilised: React, Tachyons (CSS Toolkit), API integration